

SHIVAM PANDEY

Prayagraj, India, 211004

8542944471

shivam18feb@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Knowledgeable IT team member with background setting up, maintaining, and repairing user stations. Equipped to work independently on diverse support projects and keep impeccable records. Offers expert troubleshooting, critical thinking, and problem-solving abilities. Hard working and effective web developer who has more than 1.5 years of expertise. Bilingual, astute and deadline-driven. Seeking a developer position where a strong understanding of technology and a marketing background can be best utilised.

EDUCATION

Master of Computer Application:

Software, 2021

Integral university - Prayagraj

Bachelor of Computer Application:

Computer Application, 2016

Shiats - Prayagraj

Inter mediate : Commerece, 2013 Maharishi vidya mandir - Prayagraj

High school: Science, 2013

Maharishi Vidya Mandir - Prayagraj,

UP

PROJECTS

- E commerce website in Django with MySQL database
- CV information webpage in Django
- Bank management system in python
- Shop management in python

LINK

- https://github.com/shivam18feb /Resumemaker.git
- Am working on it host own projects

EXPERIENCE

Django Backend Developer, 08/2021 to Current

Freelancer - Prayagraj, UTTAR PRADESH

- Optimised interfaces between hardware and software to enhance usability.
- Collaborated across technical and design teams to produce innovative software applications.
- Tested software solutions following standardised procedures, collating results to formulate actionable insights.
- Participated in pre-project analysis and technical assessments to ensure creation of user-friendly interface.
- Contributed to back-end experience and collaborated on APIs.
- Handled special projects designated by senior developer.
- Managed project and web strategic planning for entire team.
- Advised on measures to support web server security.
- Developed graphics for site pages following branding guidelines and best practices.
- Planned websites and applications to best showcase multimedia.

Process Associate (Technical support), 09/2020 to 08/2021

Genpact - Noida, India

- Asked customers targeted questions throughout troubleshooting to determine smart solutions.
- Acted as the direct point of contact for any escalations from first-line engineers.
- Configured SIP devices for customers.
- Kept computer hardware in excellent working condition through regular maintenance and inspections.
- Developed team communications and information for meetings.
- Engaged with customers to better understand needs and deliver excellent service.
- Inspected products and services to comply with quality standards.
- Worked with energy and enthusiasm, enhancing positive team morale and building motivation towards web development targets.
- Optimized company website traffic using SEO techniques.
- Used extensive coding knowledge to accurately link retail elements to databases, developing high-functioning web applications.

Web Developer, 02/2019 to 06/2020

Freelancer - Prayagraj, India

- Created landing pages, dashboards and web applications using Notepad++ and and php programming languages.
- Designed, built and maintained complete Eductaion and Shopping websites.
- Redesigned sites to enhance navigation and improve visual appeal.
- Defined and conducted design processes at all stages, including research, conceptualisation, testing and implementation.
- Participated in pre-project analysis and technical assessments to ensure creation of user-friendly interface.
- Contributed to back-end experience and collaborated on APIs.
- Handled special projects designated by senior developer.
- Managed project and web strategic planning for entire team.
- Worked extensively with engineering staff to better understand software solutions and their benefits to projects.

- Completed website backup and disaster recovery planning daily, reducing data hack or loss risks.
- Optimised site visuals and information processing by allocating space strategically.
- Developed graphics for site pages following branding guidelines and best practices.

CORE QUALIFICATIONS

- Computer backup management
- Case management
- Data recovery strategies
- ICT training management
- Software update installation
- Application installation
- CSS
- Content Management System (CMS) platforms

- MySQL
- Debugging
- JavaScript
- HTML
- Project management
- Apache web server
- Programming concepts

CERTIFICATIONS

- Python certified
- 6 month Django certification
- AWS Solution Architect
- Php Certification
- C and C++
- AWS Builder App Certification